Hello English learners.
Welcome back to another great
lesson here with English pot.
My name is Marco and I'm Erica
And today we're bringing
you an upper-intermediate
lesson a special lesson
about the new president right?
It's been a hot topic in the US the new
president elect president Obama. Yes
So today we're bringing
you something that you
might see at his inaugural
address. That's true
So Marco can you explain
this word inaugural address?
The inaugural address
is the first speech the
president gives at the
ceremony when he is
Officially president.
Okay. All right.
So it's his first presidential
speech. Exactly. Mm-hmm.
Great So let's take a look at
some other words that we're
going to find in the dialogue
today in vocabulary preview
vocabulary preview
Alright, I'm vocabulary preview today. We
have two words. The first one is swear-in
Swear-in swear-in
swear-in. We'll see this
word in its past tense
in the dialogue, right?
Sworn in sworn in so it means
So to swear someone in is to
officially give that person
a very important position.
Usually in government. Yeah, yeah,
and our second word is oath. Oh
oath
ATH oath and oath goes hand
in hand with swear-in, right?
That's right when you swear someone
in they make an oath a promise, right?
Promise an official promise to
carry out the duties of that job
Right, so they promise
that they will do their job.
Okay, great So now let's listen to our
dialogue for a first time. Where are we well?
We're actually watching
a news reporter on TV
She's in Washington
and she's gonna tell us all
about what's happening.
Great. So let's listen
This is Madeline right for BCC News
reporting live from Washington DC
where very shortly the new president
will deliver his inaugural address
Just a moment ago the
president was sworn into
office following the
United States Constitution
The president's ward and oath
to faithfully execute the office
of the presidency And what
exactly is going on now, Madeline?
Well Tom true to American tradition
the band has just played hail to
the chief and the president has
been honored with a 21 guns salute
Now we're waiting for the president
to take the stage and deliver his speech
Tom is like the who-to of the
political world here on Capitol
Hill with dignitaries representing
several different countries
What's the mood on the ground
like Madeline? In a word the
mood here is electric the
excitement in the air is palpable
I've never seen a larger
crowd here on Capitol Hill
The audience is shouting crying and embracing
each other on this a most historic day
You can feel the hope
and the excitement in the air
The 20th of January will
go down in history as well.
Oh Tom it looks like the
president is about to begin
My fellow American
I stand before you today
Okay, some technical problems
at the inaugural address.
Yeah, I certainly hope
this doesn't happen
Well, if it does you heard it first at
English pod predictors of the future.
Okay, let's take a look
at language takeaway
Language takeaway
On language takeaway today, we're
bringing you four words. The first word is
Deliver deliver deliver
deliver like deliver a pizza. No
Let's listen. We've got
three examples that
will show the meaning
of this word example one
Who's going to deliver the welcome speech?
Example two I've
been asked to deliver a
presentation on the findings
of our research project
example three
Dr. Rosen is delivering a
lecture on macroeconomics
Okay, so deliver a speech say
a speech to say a speech. Yeah
So you wouldn't say say a speech.
You would say deliver a speech.
Exactly. Okay. Okay. Our second
word for language takeaway
The who's who the who's
who the who's who this
is a funny expression.
Hey, it's kind of weird
The who's who is the important
people in a particular field, right? Right?
So for example, there
was a party last night and
the who's who of the film
industry was there. Whoa
So all the important stars and
directors. Yeah. Okay, you could
also say the funeral was like a
who's who of the political world
Okay, so all the important
political figures were at
this funeral exactly. Let's
move to our third word
Dignitaries dignitaries dignitaries.
Okay, we have some great examples.
You can understand what
this word means. So let's listen
example one
Several important dignitaries were
present at the opening ceremony
including the president of Brazil
the king of Spain and the poop
Example two
They're going to be a lot of
foreign dignitaries at the dinner
So basically we can understand that
dignitaries are really important people, right?
Right. Important political
or religious figures
I see. All right. Now our last word
for language take away palpable
Palpable Palpable
When something is palpable
is so strong, you can feel it.
Okay, so it's a very strong
feeling. You can almost touch it
Yeah, like the excitement
was palpable or the
fear was palpable. Okay.
Interesting word palpable
Let's listen to our dialogue
again. And now let's try
and listen to all these
words. We just talked about
Madeleine Wright for BCC news
reporting live from Washington DC where
very shortly the new president
will deliver his inaugural address
Just a moment ago the
president was sworn into
office following the
United States Constitution
The president's war and oath
to faithfully execute the office
of the presidency and what
exactly is going on now Madeleine
Well Tom true to American
tradition the band has just played hail
to the chief and the president has
been honored with a 21 gun salute
Now we're waiting for the president to
take the stage and deliver his speech Tom
It's like the who's who of the
political world here on Capitol
Hill with dignitaries representing
several different countries
What's the mood on the
ground like Madeline in a word the
motor is electric the
excitement in the air is palpable
I've never seen a larger
crowd here on Capitol Hill
The audience is shouting
crying and embracing each other
On this a most historic day you can
feel the hope and the excitement in the air
The 20th of January will
go down in history as well.
Oh Tom. It looks like the
president is about to begin
Before you today
Okay, so if you noticed in our dialogue
we have some really interesting phrases
there. Yes, so I think it's time for
us to take a look at fluency builder
Fluency builder
Unfluency builder today we're going to
be looking at three phrases that are very
interesting because we can change them
a little bit and form different patterns
Yeah, so the first phrase we have is
in a word in a word in a word in a word
We use this expression when
we want to describe something
in one word right pretty
simple. Hi. It's really simple
Let's look at the pattern. We've got
examples of how you could use this phrase
Example one
In a word the situation is serious
Example two
What's it like there in a word?
It's amazing
Okay, so in a word this podcast
is awesome. Amazing. Uh-huh.
Okay. Okay. Okay. Let's look
at our second phrase today
Go down in history go down
in history go down in history
So this is a really common phrase.
I'm sure you guys have heard it
Yeah, basically something
that is really important
that everyone will
remember for a very long time
Let's look at this pattern with
a few examples example one
This is going to go down in history as
the worst disaster the world has ever seen
Example two
You'll go down in history is
the best president we've ever had
Example three
This day we'll go down in history
Okay, so as you can see the
pattern is we're using a superlative
That's right the most the
best the biggest the worst the
worst right and our final
phrase in putting it together is
My fellow Americans my fellow
American my fellow American
so obviously you can
change this one up a little bit
Hey, right you can say
my fellow co-workers.
Uh-huh my fellow citizens
my fellow family members. Yes
So basically fellow just means
like deer yeah in some way
Well similar similar. Yeah, so we looked
at some great vocabulary and phrases
And now let's talk a little
bit about these American
traditions when electing
a new president. Yes
Today in the studio.
We have JP who's joining us. Hi everyone
Hey JP and he's going to be talking
to us about these traditions. Oh
I am okay. Yeah. What are we gonna talk
about 21 gun salute? What's that all about?
The 21 gun salute is the military
salute where they say and now
We will have the 21 gun salute
So 21 soldiers with their rifles they go
And they all shoot them off at the
same time and they don't know why
I think it's a sign of respect hey
Yeah, you'd respect those well. I think in
Europe. They would do a cannon or something
Oh right canon salute no, we'll
just cannons maybe just one
cannon maybe our European
listeners know the answer to me
Okay, and what about this song hail to
the chief? Do you know anything about that?
I do not know anything about
Except that it's a march
and I think it's Suza
I think John Phillips who's
eroded and whenever the
president walks into a room
they play that song really yes
And I played it once for
president Bush the first one.
I was a drummer you did and
my marching band had to play
that song for him Oh my
god, do you hear like famous?
Yeah, this was back in
like 1986 or something was
that even in election year
eight eight. I don't know
Well, you did play for the president.
So that's pretty cool. Yeah
So JPD have any other
sort of traditional things
that happen when the
president becomes the president
Well, um, I can tell you that Jimmy Carter
You know when when he was
elected president this motorcade was
going down Pennsylvania Avenue
and he stopped the car and got out
Really? Yeah to walk he wanted
to walk down Pennsylvania.
Yeah, but he wanted
to walk down the
You know down the street to like
to be with the people. Yeah, I think
so and I think it made the I think
it made the secret service insane
Maybe the car smelled better some
Maybe so I think that is my memory of it.
I might be confusing with
the West Wing, but I'm not
Too much TV. Yeah, maybe when
the president walks. It's a big deal.
So JP do you do anything special
for the inauguration ceremony?
I always take the day off to watch you do.
I love watching it. I love you know the
I love the swearing-in
ceremony the ritual of it the
The speech all right everyone.
We're out of time. I hope
you enjoyed this political lesson
And I hope you have a happy inauguration
day happy inauguration day. Yeah, okay
All right, great. We're definitely gonna
take the day off to watch it with JP and
Hopefully you guys
can too. Well, thanks for
listening everyone and
until next time goodbye